Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Wesley W. Posvar, Administrative Files, 1967-1991 UA.2.10.1967-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Academic Year 1972/73, VI.
  - Student Affairs, 1972-1973; 7.0.
    - Organizations, 1972-1973; 7.2
      - Student Government (Box 29, Folder 122)
    - Demonstrations (Unrest), 1972-1973; 7.3.
      - Memorial Service for Students Killed at Southern University and Students for a Democratic Society Flyer (Box 29, Folder 123)
    - Activities, 1972-1973; 7.4.
      - Activities - General (Box 29, Folder 123)
      - Commencement (Box 29, Folder 124)
        The Honorable F. Bradford Morse, Undersecretary General of the United Nations, will be Commencement Speaker, April 29, 1973; Comments and Corrections to be Made in Administration of Commencement; Bishop Roy C. Nichols requested to offer invocation and benediction at Commencement; Message to the College Graduates from President Nixon; Correspondence from various schools; and Program Script.
      - Homecoming (Box 29, Folder 125)
    - ROTC, 1972-1973; 7.5.
      - Memoranda and Reports (Box 29, Folder 126)
        National Association of Concerned Veterans letter on Veterans Programs and Regulations; School of General Studies Council reconsiders the matter of ROTC credits; The continuation of Air Force Research Associates Program with Graduate School of Public & International Affairs for academic year 1972-1973; Memos regarding Office of Veterans' Affairs; Memo regarding Veterans Tutorial Services Center, January 17, 1973; Brigadier General Robert M. White appointed Commandant of Air Force ROTC; Ellen Kingston, 1st woman ever to be commissioned in the Air Force from Air Force ROTC, University of Pittsburgh; and Annual Report of Army ROTC Activities.
    - Scholarships and Awards, 1972-1973; 7.6.
      - Correspondence (Box 29, Folder 127)
        Correspondence regarding following scholarships: Alpha Epsilon Delta expense scholarship; National Merit Scholarship; Allegheny County Medical Society Auxiliary's Scholarship; Chancellor's Scholarship; Danforth Fellowships; Board of Foreign Scholarships; Rhodes Scholarships; White House Fellows Program; Andrew Mellon Predoctoral and Postdoctoral Fellowships; National Medal of Science; Mildred Miller Posvar Music Scholarship; Graduate Fulbright Awardees; and tuition scholarships to the editors and business managers of major recognized student publications.
      - National Scholarship Committee (Box 29, Folder 128)
  - Assorted Files and Publications, 1972-1973; 8.0.
    - Pamphlets and Booklets (Box 30, Folder 129)
      Assorted pamphlets from schools; Summary Report on Deliberations, Findings and Recommendations of the 1st Vienna Seminar held at University of Vienna, July 24-28, 1972; The administration of patents of Pitt Faculty in Japan; University of Pittsburgh Campus Map; Paper on Education for the Year 2000; and University Logo.
    - Reports and University Information (Box 30, Folder 130)
    - State Board of Education (Box 30, Folder 131)
      Mr. Jerome M. Ziegler appointed Commissioner for Higher Education; 1973-74 Appropriation for Act 101, with Report of the Evaluation Team on the Act 101 Program at the University of Pittsburgh on September 12-13, 1972; Report on Reevaluation of Approved Graduate and Undergraduate Teacher Education Programs at Pitt, on January 31-February 2, 1972; Correspondence on Honorary Degrees, Academic Policy Plan for Penn State, and Guidelines for Determining Resident Status of Students at Temple University, Penn State University and Pitt; Policy Statements on Goals and Assumptions for Student Enrollment Projections, Moratorium on Establishment of Branch Campuses, and The Pennsylvania Open College; and Minutes of Meetings of Board of State College and University Directors.
    - Board of State College and University Directors Meeting Minutes (Box 30, Folder 132)
    - State Board of Education, Open College (Box 31, Folder 133)
    - Day Care Center (Box 31, Folder 134)
    - Arsenal Family and Children's Center (Box 31, Folder 135)
    - Board of Visitors (Box 31, Folder 136)
    - Black Studies (Box 31, Folder 137)
    - University-Community Educational Program (U-CEP) (Box 31, Folder 138)
    - Meeting of Pitt, Penn State and Temple Presidents (Box 31, Folder 138)
    - Carnegie Mellon, Carlow, Robert Morris and Point Park Universities Correspondence (Box 31, Folder 138)
- Academic Year 1973/74, VII.
  - Academic Programs, 1973-1974; 1.0.
    - New Careers - New Professional Association, 1973-1974; 1.1.
      - Letter Approving Expenditures for Dinner and Ceremonies for New Careers Graduates, October 5, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
    - Middle States Evaluation, 1973-1974; 1.2.
      - Reports (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
    - Provost, 1973-1974; 1.3.
      - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports (Box 1, Folder 1.3a)
        Data on women and minority graduate students, June 19, 1974; Emma W. Locke Memorial Fund and Provost Development Fund, May 31, 1974; Memo regarding Graduate Faculty Exchanges with the University of Cincinnati, May 8, 1974; Possible membership in the Argonne Universities Association and Relationship between Pitt and College of Virgin Islands; Library Services and Construction Act, May 8, 1974; Financial Aid for Graduate Students; "University-wide TA/TF Policy," Draft; letter regarding Baccalaureate programs at Pitt, March 27, 1974; Inactive Boards of Visitors in the Provost Area, March 6, 1974; Facilitation of Research Capability and Increased University Contribution to Research, January 30, 1974; The Council on Rehabilitation Education as an accrediting agency February 15, 1974; Instructional Systems Development Project, January 16, 1974; Unlawful Sale of Dissertations, December 5, 1973; Grade Change Policy, July 6, 1973; program of study open to federal employees leading to a Masters Degree in Public Administration, June 28, 1973; Research Development Fund, Policies and Procedures; Guideline Questions Regarding Progress of New Doctoral Programs; and Proposal for the Establishment of a Learning Center.
      - Women's Center; Tenure Guidelines; University Research Advisory Committee; University Council on Graduate Study; Study of Rivers; and Overhead Proposals (Box 1, Folder 1.3b)
      - Academic Integrity (Box 1, Folder 1.3c)
    - Faculty of Arts and Sciences (FAS), 1973-1974; 1.4.
      - Memoranda, Correspondence and Press Releases (Box 1, Folder 1.4a)
        Chemistry Building Dedication, November 11, 1974; Dr. Alan Fisher is recipient of NATO Fellowship for study and research at College de France; Jewish-Christian Symposium to be held in January 1974; Pitt Release regarding Pitt Conference Honors Noted Japanese Geophysicist, Professor Takesi Nagata, May 21, 1974; Newsletter, Department of Geography, May 1974; Scholarships for students with special abilities, April 11, 1974; appointment of Dr. Jake Milliones to position of Associate Director of Project Right Start; Cooperation between Pitt's Pymatuning Lab of Ecology and the ecology program of Seton Hill's biology department; "An Interdisciplinary Program in the Social and Conceptual Foundations of Medicine and the Biological Science" proposal; Recruiting additional faculty of national eminence; Dr. Robert Wolke is nominated for the Manufacturers Chemists Association Award in Chemical Education; Lists of Mellon Professors; Samuel P. Hays, Professor of History, appointed Distinguished Service Professor of History, January 28, 1974; possibility of forming a single Statistics Department to service both Carnegie-Mellon and University of Pittsburgh; Pitt Release announcing Dr. Paul F. Lazarsfeld, University Professor of Sociology, Honored by American Sociological Association, January 9, 1974; and Letter of commendation to Men's Glee Club for increasing educational relations with Mexico, January 2, 1974.
      - Reports and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1.4b)
        Letter thanking the Pittsburgh Foundation for a generous grant to Pitt's Children's Theatre Project, December 26, 1973; Draft "Rules Relating to Academic Integrity"; Faculty and Administrative Development in cooperation with West Virginia State College; Congratulatory letter to Dr. James Adovasio, Anthropology Department, regarding Rare Basket Find at Meadowcroft Village in Avella, Pa.; Reports to the Women's Studies Program; Peace Studies Semester Program; Annual Report of Academic Activities for the 1972-1973 Academic Year from Nicholas Rescher, University Professor of Philosophy and Research Professor in the Center for Philosophy of Science; Report on the Pymatuning Laboratory and library fund; Honorary Professorship bestowed upon Mr. Jerzy Grotowski of the Polish Laboratory Theatre of Philadelphia; Statement of Professor T. M. Donahue to the Subcommittee on Space Science and Application on The History of Planetary Exploration, March 15, 1972; Changes of Administrative Appointments within FAS, July 1, 1973; Cooperation in the mathematical sciences, with "Institute of Mathematical Sciences" and "Proposed Statistics Center" between Carnegie-Mellon and Pitt; and Mellon Professors.
      - Urban Studies and FAS Board of Visitors (Box 2, Folder 1.4c)
      - American Experience (Box 2, Folder 1.4d)
        Elliot Richardson's speech on March 12, 1974; Mr. William F, Buckley, Jr. lecture, May 8, 1974; Recipients of Scholarship Consideration, The American Experience, 1974; American Experience Lecturers for the future; The American Experience Class Roster, 1974, Sections 1A-2A; Governor Milton Shapp invited to introduce Mr. Robert Strauss, Chairman of Democratic National Committee, January 30, 1974; Robert G. Hazo's review of the Politics of Lying; General Maxwell Taylor Lecture; Robert Hazo's Seminar, The American Experience; and "The American Experience" booklet.
      - Pittsburgh Metropolitan Science-Technology Library (Box 2, Folder 1.4e)
      - College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) (Box 2, Folder 1.4.1)
        List of Chancellor's Undergraduate Teaching Fellowships for Fall 1974; A Proposal for A Program Leading to the Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Science; English Composition Program Progress Report; Undergraduate Urban Studies Essay Center; and Jesse J. McCorry, Jr., Associate Dean, CAS, resigns.
      - Graduate Programs (Box 2, Folder 1.4.2)
      - School of General Studies (SGS) (Box 2, Folder 1.4.3a-1.4.3b)
        Spring 74-3 Enrollments, May 24, 1974; SGS Annual Report, Greetings from Dr. Posvar at Alpha Sigma Lambda Banquet; and Correspondence regarding Arsenal Family & Children's Center.
    - Graduate School of Business (GSB), 1973-1974; 1.5.
      - GSB - General (Box 2, Folder 1.5a)
      - Zoffer Report Management (Box 3, Folder 1.5b)
      - Booklets and Pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 1.5c)
    - School of Education, 1973-1974; 1.6.
      - Correspondence and Memoranda (Box 3, Folder 1.6)
        Mrs. Jeanne H. Seaman, Associate Professor of Physical Education and innovator in the field of dance, resigns and Masoner appointed University Professor of Education and Dean Emeritus of the School of Education; Henry J. McAnulty, C.S.Sp., President of Duquesne University requests that his institute retain Dr. David Kurtzman as a Consultant; and School of Education Board of Visitors.
      - Falk School (Box 3, Folder 1.6.1)
    - School of Engineering, 1973-1974; 1.7.
      - School of Engineering - General (Box 3, Folder 1.7a)
        Dr. Max L. Williams is recipient of a 1974-1975 Fulbright-Hays Award for lecturing and research in Australia, May 22, 1974; Dr. Jack Freeman's comments on the master's degree in energy resources with Proposal for Master's Degree Program in Energy Resources, May 29, 1974; Letter of thanks to Dr. C.C. Li for being a valuable participant in the evaluation of the 1974 Engineering Research Initiation proposals for the National Science Foundation; Suspension of Search Committee Activities for the Gulf-Whiteford Chair; Center for Adhesion Science and Technology (CAST); Alcoa Foundation; and Resolution changing name of Schools of Engineering and Mines to School of Engineering, September 14, 1965.
      - Bevier Engineering Library, Board of Visitors and Gwilym A. Price Lecture (Box 3, Folder 1.7b)
    - School of Law, 1973-1974; 1.8.
      - Admissions, Tuition, Budget and Board of Visitors (Box 3, Folder 1.8)
    - Graduate School of Library and Information Sciences (GSLIS), 1973-1974; 1.9.
      - Reports and Proposals (Box 3, Folder 1.9)
    - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (GSPIA), 1973-1974; 1.10.
      - GSPIA Dean Search, Center for Arms Control and United States Air Force Research Associates (Box 3, Folder 1.10.)
      - Statement, Reports and Press Release (Box 3, Folder 1.10a)
      - Arms Control Symposium, November 1-4, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1.10b)
    - Graduate School of Social Work (GSSW), 1973-1974; 1.11.
      - Memoranda, Press Releases and Booklets (Box 4, Folder 1.11)
        Dr. Barbara K. Shore is named "Social Worker of the Year" by the Southwest Pennsylvania Chapter of the National Association of Social Workers; Lois S. Jaffe, Associate Professor of GSSW, is the first woman to be named "Man of the Year" by the Butler Area Jaycees; and Sidney A. Teller Lecture presents an address by Bertram S. Brown, M.D., Director of the National Institute of Mental Health.
    - Learning Research and Development Center (LRDC), 1973-1974; 1.12.
      - Committee on Early Childhood Program, November 19, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1.12)
      - Press Release: "Pitt's Learning Research and Development Center Receives $7,026,848 Contract from National Institute of Education", February 1, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1.12a-1.12b)
      - LRDC Cornerstone Ceremony, February 1, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1.12c)
    - Space Research Coordination Center, 1973-1974; 1.13.
      - NASA Grant NGL 39-011-080, "Research in Public Administration" (Box 4, Folder 1.13)
    - Health Professions, 1973-1974; 1.14.
      - Health Professions - General, 1.14.
        - Memoranda, Correspondence and Meetings (Box 4, Folder 1.14)
          Meeting regarding Terrace Village Health Center, April 9, 1974; Community Relations Committee of the Health Professions, January 3, 1972; Correspondence on establishment of Department of Neurosurgery in the School of Medicine; Center for Interdisciplinary Cycle Research; Community Health Association; Reorganization of Academic Medicine; Regionalization as it might relate to the Health Sciences; and Proposed Meeting Relative to the Need for a Master Plan for Medical Education.
      - School of Medicine, 1.14.1.
        - Resignation of Dr. Donald N. Medearis, Jr., Dean of School of Medicine and Salary Increases for Faculty at Montefiore Hospital (Box 4, Folder 1.14.1)
        - School of Medicine - General (Box 4, Folder 1.14.1a)
          The Dickson Prize is awarded to Dr. Stephen W. Kuffler, Professor and Chairman of the Department of Neurobiology at Harvard Medical School, October 22, 1973; The Protein Research Laboratory Annual Report, July 1, 1972-August 31, 1973; Possible establishment of a program in Nutrition Research and Education, November 16, 1973; Procedures to be implemented by all departments in all Health Center Hospital and Clinics to insure uniformity and compliance; Board of Visitors; and Gerontology.
        - A Report on the Occasion of a Visit by the Richard King Mellon Foundation and Charitable Trusts to the School of Medicine, 1953-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1.14.1a)
        - School of Medicine Board of Visitors, Gerontology and Medical School Compensation (Box 4, Folder 1.14.1b)
        - Western Psychiatric Institute and Clinic (WPIC) (Box 5, Folder 1.14.1.1)
        - Executive Committee, Faculty of Medicine (Box 5, Folder 1.14.1.2)
          Meeting Minutes and Final Regulations for the Protection of Human Subjects.
      - Graduate School of Public Health (GSPH), 1.14.2.
        - Press Release, Memoranda and Report (Box 5, Folder 1.14.2)
        - Proposals and Reports (Box 5, Folder 1.14.2a)
        - Reorganization of the Department of Epidemiology and Microbiology into Two Separate Administrative Units Known as the Department of Epidemiology and Department of Microbiology (Box 5, Folder 1.14.2b)
      - School of Dental Medicine, 1.14.3.
        - Reports and Proposals (Box 5, Folder 1.14.3)
      - School of Pharmacy, 1.14.4.
        - Proposal and Memoranda (Box 5, Folder 1.14.4)
      - School of Nursing, 1.14.5.
        - Correspondence and Memoranda (Box 5, Folder 1.14.5)
          Enid Goldberg, R.N., Ph.D., accepts position of Dean of School of Nursing with promotion to rank of Professor of General Nursing in the Department of General Nursing, effective July 1, 1973, and School of Nursing Board of Visitors.
      - School of Health Related Professions (SHRP), 1.14.6.
        - Possible Union Organization at the University Health Center and the Redesignation of the Division of Health Related Professions Instructional Services as the Division of Health Related Professions Interdisciplinary Programs (Box 5, Folder 1.14.6)
        - Correspondence and Minority Recruitment (Box 5, Folder 1.14.6a)
        - Child Development (Box 5, Folder 1.14.6b)
        - Board of Visitors - SHRP (Box 5, Folder 1.14.6c)
    - Regional Campuses, 1973-1974; 1.15.
      - Regional Campuses - General (Box 5, Folder 1.15)
        Objectives and projections for the four regional campuses and "A Report to the Provost: Development of Satellite Campuses in the Greater Pittsburgh Metropolitan Area," 1973.
      - Bradford (UPB) (Box 6, Folder 1.15.1)
      - Greensburg (UPG) (Box 6, Folder 1.15.2)
      - Johnstown (UPJ) (Box 6, Folder 1.15.3)
      - Titusville (UPT) (Box 6, Folder 1.15.4)
    - International Programs, 1973-1974; 1.16.
      - Programs and Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 1.16)
        Itinerary for visit of Ambassador of Japan and Mrs. Yasukawa, May 30, 1974; Scholarly exchange programs, International Research & Exchange Board (IREX); The Board of Trustees of the German Marshall Fund of U.S. has approved a grant of $25,000 to Pitt to Support and extend Council for European Studies, March 14, 1974; Letter of thanks for assistance and support in Japan for Pitt's Asian Studies programs, February 19, 1974; The Russian and East European Studies Program in cooperation with the Cultural Environment Program presents "The Soviet Economy and the Environmental Crisis," February 19, 1974; Professor Jan Szczepanski, Foreign Lincoln Lecturer, will lecture at Pitt, February 8, 1974; Report by Dr. Richard Pratt, Physics Department, on program with Bucharest, January 22, 1974; and Proposal for a Master of Arts Degree in East Asian Studies.
      - Reports and Events (Box 6, Folder 1.16a)
      - UN University (Box 6, Folder 1.16b)
      - OCEAC Project (Box 6, Folder 1.16c)
      - University Center for International Studies (UCIS) (Box 6, Folder 1.16.1)
        Draft Proposal to the Ford Foundation for a Center for Arms Control and International Security Affairs; Report to the Ford Foundation on the dissertation fellowship program sponsored by the Foundation through the International Studies Association with Informal report of the activities of the International Studies Association; Cole Blasier resigns as Director of the Center for Latin American Studies, effective August 31, 1974, and Carmen Mesa-Lago named Director; Report on cooperative program with Romania; and Re-establishing collaboration between Pitt and CEDA, Kathmandu, Nepal.
    - Urban Programs, 1973-1974; 1.17.
      - Grants, Pamphlets and Hudson Institute (Box 6, Folder 1.17)
    - Research Programs, 1973-1974; 1.18.
      - Center for Interdisciplinary Cycle Research and Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies (Box 6, Folder 1.18)
      - Public Interest Research Group (PIRG) (Box 6, Folder 1.18.1)
      - University Center for Urban Research (Box 6, Folder 1.18.2)
  - Athletics, 1973-1974; 2.0.
    - Athletics - General (Box 6, Folder 2.0.)
    - Director of Athletics (Box 6, Folder 2.1a)
    - Board of Visitors - Athletics (Box 6, Folder 2.1b)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) (Box 7, Folder 2.1c-2.1f)
    - Panther Foundation (Box 7, Folder 2.2)
    - Basketball and Baseball (Box 7, Folder 2.3)
    - Football (Box 7, Folder 2.4a)
    - Football - Fiesta Bowl (Box 7, Folder 2.4b)
    - Women's Sports (Box 7, Folder 2.5)
  - University Boards, Committees and Memberships, 1973-1974; 3.0.
    - Boards, Committees and Memberships - General, 1973-1974; 3.0.
      - Graduation, Elna Lucrezia Cornaro Piscopia Tercentenary Committee and 50th Anniversary of National Jewish Campus Ministry (Box 7, Folder 3.0.)
      - Awards and Summaries (Box 7, Folder 3.0a)
      - Heinz Memorial Chapel (Box 7, Folder 3.0b)
      - Stephen Foster Memorial (Box 7, Folder 3.0c)
      - Chaplains' Association (Box 7, Folder 3.0d)
      - World Affairs Council (WAC) (Box 7, Folder 3.0e)
    - Board of Trustees, 1973-1974; 3.1.
      - Board of Trustees - General (Box 7, Folder 3.1-3.1a)
      - Redefinition of Missions: The University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg and Titusville (Box 8, Folder 3.1b)
      - Commonwealth Trustees, Board of Visitors, University President Inaugurals and Board of Trustees Handbook (Box 8, Folder 3.1c)
      - By-Laws (Box 8, Folder 3.1.1)
      - Budget-Audit Committee (Box 8, Folder 3.1.2)
      - Academic Affairs (Box 8, Folder 3.1.3)
      - Student Affairs Committee (Box 8, Folder 3.1.4)
      - Committee on the Health Professions (Box 8, Folder 3.1.5)
      - Executive Committee (Box 8, Folder 3.1.6)
      - Facilities Committee (Box 8, Folder 3.1.7)
    - Advisory Boards, 1973-1974; 3.2.
      - Bradford (Box 8, Folder 3.2.1)
      - Greensburg (Box 8, Folder 3.2.2)
      - Johnstown (Box 9, Folder 3.2.3)
      - Titusville (Box 9, Folder 3.2.4)
    - Council of Deans, 1973-1974; 3.3.
      - Chancellor's Remarks and Meeting Minutes (Box 9, Folder 3.3)
    - Senate Council, 1973-1974; 3.4.
      - Senate Council Members and Meeting Minutes, June 1973-January 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3.4a)
      - Meeting Minutes and Chancellor's Remarks (Box 9, Folder 3.4b)
    - University Senate, 1973-1974; 3.5.
      - University Senate - General (Box 9, Folder 3.5a)
      - Senate Agendas and Meetings (Box 9, Folder 3.5b)
      - Admissions and Student Aid Committee (Box 9, Folder 3.5c)
      - Budget Policies Committee (Box 9, Folder 3.5d)
      - Liaison Committee (Box 10, Folder 3.5e)
      - University Governance Committee (Box 10, Folder 3.5f)
      - Commonwealth and Community Relations Committee (Box 10, Folder 3.5g)
      - Computer Usage, Health & Welfare, Library, Organization & Procedures, Plant Utilization & Planning, Student Affairs and Tenure & Academic Freedom Committees (Box 10, Folder 3.5h)
      - Education Policies (Box 10, Folder 3.5i)
      - External Degree Program (USEP) (Box 10, Folder 3.5.1)
      - University Athletic Committee Members and Proposed Reorganization (Box 10, Folder 3.5.2)
      - University Athletic Committee Meeting Minutes, Reports and Proposals (Box 10, Folder 3.5.2a)
      - Preliminary Athletic Eligibility Report for Special Aid Awards Recommendation Group, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 3.5.2b)
    - Official Memberships, 1973-1974; 3.6.
      - World Society for Ekistics (Box 10, Folder 3.6a)
      - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC), Committee on Urban Problems (Box 10, Folder 3.6b-3.6c)
      - NASULGC Pamphlets (Box 10, Folder 3.6d)
      - NASULGC, Financing Post-Secondary Education and Low Tuition (Box 11, Folder 3.6e)
      - NASULGC Circular Letters (Box 11, Folder 3.6f)
      - NASULGC Correspondence and Meeting Minutes (Box 11, Folder 3.6g)
      - The Academy for Educational Development, Inc. (Box 11, Folder 3.6h)